sixteen thousand eight fifty seven we
have amit gupta vice president and pms
fund manager at icc securities now
joining us to take some questions amit
good to have you with us here thanks
very much for your time
uh you know so 238 solid games
financials are leading from the front
the question though is uh is this uh you
know is this going to last or once again
it will be
you know a bit of snakes and ladder
uh up and down over and over again like
what we've seen for the last fortnight
or so what is your sense the broader
market is not participating i was just
pointing out that uh it's almost one is
to our advances to declines it's large
cap led and they're also
you know very bunchy financials are
doing well it's doing well and a few
other things what's your sense so i
think first of all important point is if
you look at the large cap and mid cap
earnings yield it is hardly one percent
difference and that is where large caps
are much more lucrative and considering
the fact you are entering into the
interest rate hike cycle i think that is
that is something that one should look
at having you know more large caps in
the portfolio whether it is from the
value space or from the high growth
space because i think valuations do
matter because if you look at right now
what we saw in the month of january and
february most of the richly valued you
know sectors they have seen the profit
booking in the market and that money
possibly you know go into the value
space and that can make your portfolios
more balanced i think going forward so
that is how i think we should look at
this market and eventually you know
these events will come and will go
because i think whatever russia ukraine
event which is creating volatility we
had india makes around 30 to 33
which has also cooled off now but i
think the major kick will come when it
will come below 20 now
and by that time i think the the major
the other major variable was the
interest rate hike and we have seen
historically in the last two decades
whatever jitters come before the first
rate hike actually that creates an
opportunity because the bond yields move
actually come before the first rate hike
majorly and not during the rate you look
at 2004 2006 rate hike cycle which was
almost four percent and we saw only 39
bits of increase in the bond yields and
that is why markets moved up actually
when the rate hike started you look at
2016 2018 rate high so that time 2.25
percent the interest rates were
increased but bond yields moved up only
by 79 bits so i think this is where you
know the truth is and because bond
yields in us they already moved up from
0.5 percent to 2 percent i think in
anticipation of six or seven rate hikes
that move has already come in so markets
will find breather
i think and that is creating an
opportunity in stock specifics now okay
uh i'm at high good afternoon so in
terms of stock specific action where do
you see more traction going forward
so i think broadly uh if you've seen a
banking technology metals and energy and
i think these four space if you look at
the eps of nifty
it is not getting downgraded actually
despite the crude moving higher
because matters if you combine all of
them they are in excess of 60 percent of
the nifty weight right
and banking primarily the the you know
the results are coming better from the
big banks actually the big nvfc's or the
big private banks or psus i think we
should one should avoid the mid cap
banking and uh you know or the lower the
spectrum nbfcs right now i think that is
where the major problem is if you look
at the last one year or so we had seen
lot of exposure of smes by the mid cap
banks for example city union bank or
idfc first bank we had seen lot of
exposure and that is where the
restructuring book is much larger there
even up to the size of six percent but
the larger banks have a restructuring of
only 0.6 look at excess bank and 0.6
percent of restructuring we saw look at
the other larger banks it is 1.4 1.3 so
that gives comfort and also the
provisioning has gone to 70 more than 70
percent in the larger banks while in a
smaller banks it is still around 34 or
50 percent but even even if you take the
case of au small finance bank also where
it is 50 percent of provisioning that
does not give comfort actually at these
levels and that is why i think one
should remain there in the larger banks
right now where your valuations also are
coming better now
um
uh amit uh have you raised any cash in
the last couple of months i remember the
last time around you were saying you
were sitting on some cash i you up that
level
so
really actually we don't believe in
coming in too much of cash because we
feel uh there is enough opportunity you
know in many sectors which had not
performed in the last 10 12 years there
may be some jitters there for example
telecom space there may be some jitters
over there but the things the way the
things are shaping up now i mean the way
the rpus are increasing and the way you
know the free cash flows are coming back
into the bigs of telecom companies the
capex is already mostly done i think
this is pro this will provide you know
much much better uh move there so we
should remain invested so i cannot time
actually all these cycles in the market
right now how many people would have
timed this move from you know 15 800 to
now almost closer to sixteen thousand
eight hundred so this difficult one one
thing we need to understand is that
there are many sectors available right
now for example capital goods we are
writing the valuations are now slowly
coming better and in fact as i said
about the larger banks so this is one
area that should be part of your
portfolios and you should remain
invested
um and amit when you're talking about
telecom stocks uh you're referring to
the core uh telecom play you're looking
at uh you know the player that's
struggling a bit or you're looking at uh
you know the other player that has
different other businesses as well what
would it be the core play bharti hotel
i think definitely yes because that is
also part of our portfolio and we
started buying the stock actually when
there was an expectation that its weight
in msci is going to be increased because
if you remember around 600 there was
some selling by the promoters and that
is where the free float in the stock
increased and then immediately
afterwards we saw in msci the weight of
the stock increased by double so from
almost 1.4 i think it moved to almost
three percent in that particular index
so we started buying actually before
that and we are holding because now the
rpus if you see the even the promoters
when they are coming they are talking
about more than 200 rupees of artwork
going ahead if you see how the south
africa business is turning around lot of
opportunities are there and in india
because very
very very number of players have become
you know shrunk like anything i think
the subscriber base eventually will
increase in you know these limited
players and because the prepaid prices
actually have increased because that
comprises more than 80 percent of the
revenues of telecom companies i think
this is where the major push is coming
now and most of the capex is already
done whatever money they raise through
the rights issue they are delivering the
balance sheet and that is where i think
you have not seen that kind of
correction coming in that stock i think
the downsides are very very limited
there and it's an opportunity again
coming there because you are getting i
think 10 15 lower now
and capital goods amit what do you like
there what stocks
so i think uh where we are focusing more
right now is uh along with the banking
and telecom i think as i said capital
goods because government capex uh is
something you know which has got doubled
now if you see when this government came
in 2014 it was hardly 1.5 percent of gdp
the capex was which was very standard
capex but in the last two years it has
gone to 2.4 percent of gdp in and if i
believe whatever has come out in budget
despite you know all the
hurdles which are coming up right now so
slowly the things starts getting
normalized and government goes to 2.9 of
gdp it will be double
and then in that case i think who is
going to be the beneficiary i think the
capital goods companies definitely their
order book is going to increase the
companies which are selling the non-core
assets like for example larsen and to
grow i think they are going to bounce
back very quickly and that is where
actually we have positioned our
portfolio you know quite a sizable
position there and we are quite hopeful
because first of all you what you need
to catch here in this market is the
valuations if the growth story is there
and your valuations are becoming
attractive and the downside seems to be
limited i think this is where you should
increase your holdings and that is what
we have done here okay by the way just
look at the impulses and i don't know
why i'm you know
specifically mentioning that it's now
moved within three point five percent of
its all-time high this month infosys is
up ten percent and that compares to two
percent for tcs
uh uh and of course of course in tcu
there was some pre-buying ahead of uh
the buy-back uh but invoices this month
is up ten percent and if you compare it
to any other i t stock hcl tech or any
other stock it's a rank outperformer uh
there it is uh you see the one month
performance i think the better parameter
would be to compare it to the even nifty
it index uh yeah there it is the
comparison with hcl tech but if you even
compare it with the with the nifty it
index uh there's clearly a rank
outperformance by about five percent or
so but i mean let me make this my last
question to you on infosys in particular
what would be your view
see this is again very surprising i
understand we are coming out of pandemic
the orders for digitization are
increasing but such a growth
in such a you know seasonally quarter of
quarter three what we saw again very
very robust results from the iit company
the stocks declined because of
valuations
and now i think the heartening thing is
if you compare the large cap and the mid
cap it's right now the difference x
because mid cap id had had moved up very
fast i think that is cooling off now and
that is where i think the opportunities
are coming in the large caps because
that valuation gap actually is uh
getting better for the large cap
perspective and the buyback is already
in place so if you see the revenue
growth around 16 and a half percent what
they decided in the last quarter now
again they increased to 19 and a half
percent hiring is still very very robust
in fact i have seen a lot of consultants
coming up now just on the back of lot of
id hiring right now in the market and
that is something you know uh very very
surprisingly very positive surprise that
it is such such a consistent growth we
are seeing another point if you see the
margins because when there is a lot of
attrition lot of people moving actually
from one company to another jobs they
are getting so
packages are going higher wage cost
increases so attrition rate of 18 around
in the ide that is definitely creating
the margin pressure but because they
have entered into a lot of digital
technologies whether it is iot or
blockchain or you know cloud computing
so this is almost 58 of the revenues you
talked about infosys out of 100 rupees
or revenues it is 50 rupees actually for
infosys now and where the margins are
higher and this is the focus actually
and that is where whatever 20 to 24
percent of margins they decide
they are coming always almost closer to
24 percent the higher band which is i
think uh will not lead the stock to
decline very significantly despite the
valuations still are relatively higher
so this is a story where the growth is
there i need to write this actually with
some kind of you know uh
you know efforts because the valuations
are still little higher okay all right
thanks a lot amit for stopping by and
filling us in with all those details a
quick point on tcs and infosys remember
when the buyback announcement came tcs
was trading at close to 20 times you
know the the multiple was percent higher
than what infosys was getting now post
this recent under performance of dcs
just pull up the last one month chart or
so that is reduced to closer around four
to one five percent i think post this
recent move it'll be it'll now be just a
couple of percentage points or in terms
of the multiple that tcs gets in
comparison to emphasis so that entire
gap has got narrowed down just want to
make that quick point well we'll slip
into a short break when you come back